So let's try a few examples.
那么我们来看几个例子
So I'll create a dictionary.
我要创建一个字典
We're using the squiggly brackets.
然后使用花括号
And some keyboards that's the shift on the square bracket key.
在某些键盘上 它是 shift 加方括号键
It may be somewhere else on your keyboard.
也可能在键盘上的其他位置
And we're going to use the squiggly bracket,
我们用花括号
list our elements in the dictionary.
列出字典中的元素
So each element of the dictionary is a key value pair.
字典的每个元素都是一个键值对
And the entries in the dictionary will be the elements and their atomic
字典中的条目将是元素及其原子
numbers, so we have the string hydrogen with its atomic number 1.
序数 我们有字符串 hydrogen 及其原子序数 1
And we have carbon with number 6.
和 carbon 及其序数 6
So we've created the dictionary,
那么我们成功创建了字典
and what we see when we print it out is the elements of the dictionary.
将它打印出来时 我们会看到字典的元素
Now one thing you might notice is,
你可能会注意到一点
they're not in the same order that we put them there.
它们的顺序和我们所放置的顺序不一样
If you think about what we did with hash tables, this isn't so surprising.
如果你想一下我们创建哈希表时的情形 这就不足为奇了
When we put elements in hash tables, well where they end
当我们在哈希表中放置元素时 它们最终
in the hash table depends on the key and the hash function.
在表中的位置取决于键和哈希函数
It's not necessarily in the order that we put them in.
而不一定是我们放置的位置
And with the dictionary, because it's implemented like a hash table,
那么对于字典 因为它的实现与哈希表一样
we see the same thing.
所以也是一样的道理
Unlike a list,
它们不像列表一样
where the elements are ordered, with a dictionary there's no order to elements.
所有的元素都是有序的 字典的元素是无序的
So when we print it out,
所以当我们把它打印出来时
they might appear in a different order from the order that we put them in.
它们的顺序会与我们放置的顺序不同
We can use the indexing to lookup one of the elements.
我们可以使用索引来查找其中一个元素
So now when we lookup the value associated with hydrogen, we get one.
现在 我们查找与 hydrogen 关联的值 就会得到 1
And if we lookup the value associated with carbon, we get six.
查找与 carbon 关联的值 就会得到 6
What do you think's going to happen if we look up a value that's not in
那如果我们查找字典中没有的一个值 你认为
the dictionary?
会发生什么？
So now we're looking up the value associated with lithium.
现在我们查找与 lithium 关联的值
And what we get is an error.
我们会得到一个错误
It's called the KeyError.
称为 KeyError
KeyError, it says that element is not in the dictionary.
KeyError 它说明此元素不在字典中
This is different from how we define lookup for our hash table, right?
这和我们在哈希表中定义的查询不同 是不是？
We defined our lookup to return none, when the element is not there.
我们定义了在元素不存在的情况下返回 none (无)
The way the built in dictionary type works,
而构建的这个字典类型
is it gives us an error when it's not there.
在不存在元素的情况下向我们返回错误
If we don't want to get errors like that,
如果我们不想得到这样的错误
we can use the in, to see if an element's in the dictionary.
我们可以使用 in 来看看元素是否在字典中
So the in, behaves similarly to in did for lists.
这里的 in 与列表中 in 的行为类似
We can say lithium in elements.
我们可以说 ‘lithium’ in elements
That will evaluate to true, if the key is in the dictionary, false otherwise.
如果键在字典中 它会给出 True 否则会给出 False
So now, hit a value it's to false.
那么现在 对这个键来说　命令执行结果是 False
So I said that dictionaries were mutable, so we can add new elements.
我之前说过 字典是可变的 也就是说我们可以添加新元素
And the way to add an element, is just to use an assignment.
添加元素的方式 就是使用赋值
So we'll add lithium, giving it value 3.
我们添加 lithium 给它一个值 3
Note that it was an error, when we used an element like this as a lookup.
注意我们之前在查询这个元素时 出现了错误
When it's on the left side of an assignment, well that's an update.
当它在赋值的左侧时 即为更新
So that corresponds to the hash table update.
它对应一项哈希表更新
Where lithium is the key and 3 is the value.
lithium 为键 而 3 是它的值
We can add another element.
我们可以添加另一个元素
Let's add another element.
下面再来添加一个元素
We'll add nitrogen.
我们添加 nitrogen
And now when we look up nitrogen, we get the value that we assigned to nitrogen,
现在 我们查找 nitrogen 就会得到赋予 nitrogen 的值
which is 8.
即 8
Turns out that 8 is not actually the correct value.
事实上 8 不是正确的答案
That the atomic number for nitrogen should be seven.
nitrogen 的原子序数应该为 7
So we can modify that value, using another assignment.
那我们可以用另一个赋值修改它的值
That's again the same as our hash table update.
再一次 它和哈希表更新一样
It won't create a new key value because the key nitrogen is already there.
它不会创建一个新的键值 因为键 nitrogen 已经存在了
But it will update the value, so
但是它会更新这个值
now the value associated with nitrogen will be 7.
现在 与 nitrogen 关联的值为 7
So we can see the first print, the value is 8.
可以看到第一次打印的值是 8
The second print, the value is now 7.
而现在第二次打印的值是 7